# **Rommel Martinez**

# Full-stack Web Developer

96 Fieldstone Court, Fredericton, NB E3A 9P3 | 506-476-1555 rommelvmartinez@gmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/rommel-martinez-476003183/ | https://rommelmartinez.com/

## **Professional Summary**

With nine years of work experience in full-stack web development, throughout my career, I have successfully developed and deployed applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework Core, JavaScript, CSS3, and RESTful API along with designing database table structures in SQL Server.

## **Professional Experience**

# **Full-stack Web Developer**

Jan 2022 - Oct 2023

Outreach Productions Inc, Hanwell NB

- Developed and maintained web applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC, Bootstrap, JavaScript, RESTful API, and MudBlazor for Front-End and Back-End development and SQL Server.
- Developed Object-Oriented codes, makes programs more efficient and easy to understand.
- Conducted and validated functions while executing unit tests.
- Designed applications user-friendly interface to make the user's experience easy and intuitive.
- Created and maintained Entity Framework Core (Code First) which creates databases from model and store data to the database.
- Successfully managed multiple applications, often as a solo developer in high-pressure and fast-paced environments.

#### **Computer Programmer**

Sep 2014 - Dec 2021

Almana General Hospital, Saudi Arabia

- Developed hospital applications using C# .NET, focusing on efficiency and data integrity.
- Designed and maintained classes for Data Access Layer and Entity Manager to simplify access of a storage such as entity relational database.
- Created database in SQL Server, stored procedures, tables and indexes to enhance data retrieval.
- Developed and maintained stored procedures (Insert, Update, Select, Delete, XML) to ensure efficient database operations.
- Created descriptive reports using Crystal Reports, offering valuable insights and data visualization.

#### **Education**

# **Bachelor of Science (B.S.) - Computer Science** STI College

Jun 2007 - Mar 2012

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Object-Oriented, C#, .Net Framework, Entity Framework Core, ASP.NET MVC, MudBlazor, RESTful API, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery, SQL Server, Python Django, IIS Server, React JS